<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "SIP_Presence_Service_User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter
	id="sps-SIP_Presence_Server">
	<title>&PLATFORM_NAME; SIP Presence Server</title>
	<para>The <application>&PLATFORM_NAME; SIP Presence Server</application> is a free and open source implementation of a SIP Presence Server, as defined by the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF), the Open Mobile Alliance (OMA), the 3rd Generation Partnership Project (3GPP) and the European Telecommunications Standards Institute (ETSI).</para>
	<para>The <application>SIP Presence Server</application> is an entity that accepts, stores and distributes SIP presence information, fully supporting OMA Presence SIMPLE Data Extensions V1.2.</para>
	<section
		id="sps-Functional_Architecture_of_the_SIP_Presence_Server">
		<title>Functional Architecture of the SIP Presence Server</title>
		<para>The <application>SIP Presence Server</application> is comprised of the following functional elements:</para>
		<variablelist
			id="sps-Functional_Elements_of_the_SIP_Presence_Server">
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Presence Publication Control</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>This functional element manages the publication of presence events, which includes the handling of new publications and the refreshing, modification or removal of already-published information.</para>
					<para>This element is also responsible for composing all of the different publications for the same resource. This is because the presence resource, which is also called a <emphasis>presentity</emphasis>, can have multiple publications simultaneously, such as some states published by a user agent or device, and some location data published by a Presence Network Agent (on behalf of the presentity).</para>
					<para>In some presence networks, it may be of interest to allow resources to have a static presence state stored in the XDM Server. In cases like these, Presence Publication Control may need to interface with the <application>XDM Server</application> to retrieve and subscribe to (learn about changes to) that information, and use it when composing the final presence information document.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Presence Content Manipulation Control</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>This functional element is responsible for subscribing presence content stored in the XDMS, create and manage the related publications in the Presence Publication Contro.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Presence Subscription Control</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>This functional element handles subscriptions to presence events or to the list of subscribers (watchers) for any specific resource. It is responsible for emitting notifications related to those subscriptions.</para>
					<para>Presence authorization rules, which define if a subscription is allowed or rejected and, if allowed, define which transformations to the original presence events are needed, are stored on the <application>XDM Server</application> by the user. Presence Subscription Control needs to retrieve and subscribe to that information.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Presence Rules Cache</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>This element is responsible for interfacing with the <application>XDM Server</application> that manages the user's XML presence rules documents. It is responsible for providing the presence rules to the Presence Subscription Control, which are used to authorize the subscriptions it handles.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		
	</section>
	<section
	id="sps-Configuring_The_Sip_Presence_Server">
		<title>Configuring The SIP Presence Server</title>
		<para>Several features of the SIP Presence Server are configurable, through XML files or JMX:</para>			
		<section id="sps-Configuring_the_Abstract_SIP_Event_Publication_Interface">
			<title>Configuring the Abstract SIP Event Publication Interface</title>
			<para>Edit the properties in file <filename>$JBOSS_HOME/server/&lt;server_profile&gt;/deploy/mobicents-sip-presence/3-beans/configuration/sip-event/publication/META-INF/jboss-beans.xml</filename>.</para>
			<para>This configuration part can also be done through JMX, using the <emphasis>org.mobicents.sippresence:name=SipEventPublicationControl</emphasis> MBean. The configuration changes through JMX are not persistent.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="sps-Configuring_the_Abstract_SIP_Event_Subscription_Interface">
			<title>Configuring the Abstract SIP Event Subscription Interface</title>
			<para>Edit the properties in file <filename>$JBOSS_HOME/server/&lt;server_profile&gt;/deploy/mobicents-sip-presence/3-beans/configuration/sip-event/subscription/META-INF/jboss-beans.xml</filename>.</para>
			<para>This configuration part can also be done through JMX, using the <emphasis>org.mobicents.sippresence:name=SipEventSubscriptionControl</emphasis> MBean. The configuration changes through JMX are not persistent.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="sps-Configuring_the_Concrete_SIP_Event_Interfaces">
			<title>Configuring the Concrete SIP Event Interfaces</title>
			<para>Edit the properties in file <filename>$JBOSS_HOME/server/&lt;server_profile&gt;/deploy/mobicents-sip-presence/3-beans/configuration/sip-presence/META-INF/jboss-beans.xml</filename>.</para>
			<para>This configuration part can also be done through JMX, using the <emphasis>org.mobicents.sippresence:name=SipPresenceServerManagement</emphasis> MBean. The configuration changes through JMX are not persistent.</para>
		</section>		
	</section>
	<section
	id="sps-Content_Accepted_By_The_Sip_Presence_Server">
		<title>Content accepted by the SIP Presence Server</title>
		<para>The <application>&PLATFORM_NAME; SIP Presence Server</application> accepts the following content type to be published and subscribed by users:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<ulink url="http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc3863">IETF Presence Information Data Format - PIDF (RFC 3863)</ulink>
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<ulink
					url="http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4479">A Data Model for Presence (RFC 4479)</ulink>
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<ulink
					url="http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4480">IETF Rich Presence Information Data format - RPID (RFC 4480)</ulink>
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<ulink url="http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4481">IETF Timed Presence Extensions (RFC 4481)</ulink>
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<ulink
					url="http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4482">IETF Contact Information in Presence Information Data Format - CIPID (RFC 4482)</ulink>
			</para>
		</listitem>		
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<ulink url="http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4199">IETF A Presence-based GEOPRIV Location Object Format - GEOPRIV (RFC 4199)</ulink>
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<ulink url="http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc5196">IETF SIP UA Capability Extension to Presence Information Data Format (RFC 5196)</ulink>
			</para>
		</listitem>
		
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<ulink
					url="http://www.openmobilealliance.org">OMA Extensions to PIDF and Presence Data Model</ulink>
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<ulink
					url="http://www.openmobilealliance.org">OMA PDE - Presence SIMPLE Data Extension 1.0</ulink>
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<ulink
					url="http://www.openmobilealliance.org">OMA PDE - Presence SIMPLE Data Extension 1.1</ulink>
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>		
	<important>
		<para>The content accepted can be easily extended/modified, one just need to add/remove the related XML schema files in the directory <filename>$JBOSS_HOME/server/&lt;server_profile&gt;/deploy/mobicents-sip-presence/3-beans/configuration/sip-presence/xsd</filename>.</para>
	</important>
	</section>
</chapter>
